Carter Newman Bealer Papers WLU.Coll.0094
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Carter Newman Bealer Papers
1905-1962
1930-1950
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Bealer, Carter Newman
WLU.Coll.0094
28.3 Linear Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Bealer estate, 1965.
Biographical / Historical
Bealer was a student at Washington and Lee University from 1918-1922.
Scope and Contents
Includes family and business correspondence and a variety of private collections, such as diaries, playbills, ship menus, as well as a significant collection of autographed photographs and letters of late 19th and early 20th century theatrical and musical performers.
Playbills; Correspondence; Autographs; Actors; Musicians; Wilcox family; Gray, Harry L.; Hayward, Ella; Peebles, L.H.; Westheimer, Milton J.
- Scrapbooks
  - Theatre Scrapbook
    Separated Materials
    This item is located with the other playbills.
  - Miscellaneous Scrapbooks, 6 Volumes (Box 12)
    Scope and Contents
    This box contains 6 scrapbooks: 3 not labeled, 2 labeled 'Heraldry Scrapbook', and 1 labeled 'A Memory Book'.
  - Miscellaneous Scrapbook, 2 Volumes (Box 13)
    This box contains 2 scrapbooks. One is labeled 'Autograph Book' and the other is labeled 'Hotel cards'.
- Business and Legal Documents (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - 1896 Georgia State Tax Card and related items Signed Mrs. E. J. W. Bealer
    Bealer, E. J. W.
  - E.J. W. Bealer Tax Records for 1906
  - Atlantic and Pacific Tea Company Correspondence, 1906
    Bealer, Pierre McFarland
  - Various Work Orders for Business/Construction in Georgia, 1900-1910
  - Papers regarding a dispute of title from the Law Offices of Daley, Chambers, and Smith, 1909-09
  - Papers regarding the Southern Baptist Convention of Asheville, NC, 1916-05
  - San Diego, California Real Estate License for P.M. Bealer, 1923
  - Estate Papers for P.M. Bealer, executed by Carter Newman Bealer, 1954-09
    Bealer, Carter Newman; Bealer, Pierre McFarland
- Playbills, 17 Box
  The boxes relating to playbills are located in the playbills part of the Closed Stacks.
  - Scrapbook- Playbills
    Envelope labeled Scrapbook-Playbills
  - Playbills- Continental (Severn Duvall Gift)
    This box is located with the other playbills.
  - Notebooks with Playbills, 13 Volumes
    These notebooks are is located with the other playbills.
  - Playbills- Continental A-Z
  - Playbills- Continental A-Z
  - Souvenir Playbills (English)
  - Souvenir Playbills (English)
  - Souvenir Playbills (English)
  - Souvenir Playbills- English and American
  - Playbills- A
  - Playbills- B (I)
  - Playbills- B (II)
  - Playbills- C
  - Playbills- D-G
  - Playbills- H (I)
  - Playbills- H (II)
  - Playbills- I
  - Playbills- J
  - Playbills- K-L
  - Playbills- M
  - Playbills- N-O
  - Playbills- P
  - Playbills- Q-R
  - Playbills- S
  - Playbills- T
  - Playbills- U-Z and Autographed Playbills
- Correspondence, 1905-1962
  - Christmas Cards, 1885-1950 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Christmas Cards, 1951-1955 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Christmas Cards, 1956-1961; No Dates (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Miscellaneous - Various Correspondences (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Miscellaneous - Various Correspondences and Mailings (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence, 1954-1959 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1960-01-1960-08 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1960-09-1960-12 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, No Date (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Control Folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1905-1918 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1940-01-1940-08 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1940-09 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1940-10-1940-12 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Photographs and Prints
  - Foreign Poster Cards (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Foreign Poster Cards (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Foreign Poster Cards (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 45A)
  - Photographs of Family (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Photographs by Carter Bealer (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Other Photographs (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Postcard Pictures of Theatre People, 18th-19th centuries (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - French Theatre Prints (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - French Theatre Prints (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - French Theatre Prints (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - French and Mixed Theatre Prints (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Prints- Miscellaneous (English and Composers) (Box 2, Folder 30A)
  - Photographs of Theatre People- most autographed (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Autographed Photos of Theatre People (Box 2, Folder 31A)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 2, Folder 31B)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Photographs of Theatre People (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Ephemera
  - Bookplates, HMS Pinafore, FDR inauguration souvenirs, Art catalog
  - Opera, Music, Ballet Programs
  - The Moscow Art Theatre: Theatre Guide of London; Gallery of Plays and Players; Serials; Periodicals and Misc.; Cinema Items
  - Miscellaneous - Blank Card Stock from Cruise Liners & Inaugural Ball Card for McKinley-Hobart Election, 1930-1940; 1897-03-04 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Ship Menus - Various Lines, 1895-1940 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Ship Menus - United Fruit Companies, 1930-1940 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Ship Menus - United States Line, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Ship Menus - Norwegian American Line, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Ship Menus - French Line, S.S. France, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Ship Menus - French Line, S.S. Liberté, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Ship Menus - French Line, S.S. Ile De France, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Savage Club, Other Club Programs, 1915-1935 (Box 6, Folder 7A)
  - Travel Literature - Various, 1920-1950 (Box 6, Folder 71)
- Biographies
  - Biographies: A-E (Box 4, Folder 52A)
  - Biographies: F-L (Box 4, Folder 53A)
  - Biographies: M-Sa (Box 4, Folder 54A)
  - Biographies: Se-Z (Box 4, Folder 55A)
  - Typed Biographies of Theatre People, 1930-1950 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    Includes biographies of the Incorporated Stage Socety, Fritzi Scheff, Frances Star, Sir William Bruce, Neil Hamilton, Barbara Bel Geddes, James A. Michener, Edith Fellows, and Glenda Farrel.
- Autographs
  - Autographed Checks and Receipts (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Autographed Checks and Receipts (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Check payable to Edward Everett signed Andrew Stevenson for $50, 1831-12-12
      Everett, Edward; Stevenson, Andrew
    - Stock certificate showing Leonard C. William is entitled to 4 shares of capital stock of the Mystic National Bank in Connecticut, 1870-1-24
      Williams, Leonard C.; Mystic National Bank (Connecticut)
    - Signature of "Alben W. Barkley" (torn off of a check), 1952
      Barkley, Alben William
    - Receipt for Mr D. Scorie for Joseph Bradley Furniture, 1849-11-28
      Stovil, D.; Joseph Bradley Furniture
    - Two checks written by E. Clemens, one to Senator Max Barnboker for $1 (1955) and another to Rockwell Kent for 50 cents (1954)., 1954-04-20; 1955-06-6
      Kent, Rockwell; Barnboker, Senator
    - Deposit slip for $550 for John Mopeley to the credit of George Hinmria from the New Haven County Bank, 1847-11-23
      Mopeley, John; New Haven County Bank
  - Autographs: A-E (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Autographs: F-L (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Autographs: M-Sa (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Autographs: Se-Z (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Autographs: Letters Unidentified (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Naval Autographs (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Diaries
  - Diaries, 1863-1960; 9 Volumes (Box 7)
    This box includes diaries from Virginia Cloud, Mary Cloud, Joseph W. Collins, Mrs. Gassett, and unidentified authors.
  - Diaries of Mae Douglas Drown, 1920-1930; 11 Volumes (Box 8)
  - Diaries of Mae Douglas Drown, 1931-1939; 8 Volumes (Box 9)
  - Diaries, 1940-1946; 5 Item (Box 10)
    This box contains diaries written by Mae Douglas Drown and Marian Drown.
  - Diaries, 1890-1958; 12 Volumes (Box 11)
    This box includes diaries written by Harry L. Gray, Ella Hayward, L.H. Peebles, Milton Westheimer, and Wilcox.
- Clippings
  - Lillie Langtry Clippings (Box 4, Folder 53B)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - Newspaper Clipping of Joe Di Maggie in Baltimore, MD
    - Newspaper Clippings of Various Plays, Actors, and Playwrights in Chicago
    - New York Times Book Review on WIlliam Goldhunt's Biography of F. Scott Fitzgerald, "F. Scott Fitzgerald and His Contemporaries", 1963-07-21
    - The New York Times Newspaper Photograph of Manhattan's Church of Transfiguration
    - The New York Times Book Review on Richard Church's 1956 Autobiography- "Suddenly I Was Armed with a Weapon: A Distinguished Author Relives His Boyhood and His Discovery that Poetry Was a Sword", 1956-08-05
    - Philadelphia Inquirer Spread - Women's Clothing modeled by Hollywood Movie Stars on one side and drawings of the freak Pacific Weather on the reverse, 1940-1950
  - Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Chicago Sun Newspaper Clipping on the fighter plane crash that killed Collin Kelly Written by W.L. White, 1913-09-07
    - Chicago Tribune Newspaper Clipping - "Ten Years Ago This Week She Killed Two Friends" Article on Winnie Ruth's murder of two close friends, 1941-10-12
    - The New York Times Newspaper Clipping - "Walking Tours of Dublin", 1963-07-28
  - Newspaper Clipping of Jo Di Maggio's Regarding Ankle Injuries in Baltimore, MD.
- Miscellaneous
  - Cartoon Envelopes (Box 4, Folder 57A)
  - Materials Regarding Harry Leroy Gray, 1920-1960 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Series of Photographs of Harry Leroy Gray
    - Collection of letters between Gray and his mother, 1890-1910
  - Miscellaneous - Carter Newman Bealer's Passport, small thought journals, and hand-written newspaper, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Miscellaneous - Various Papers, 1918-1950 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Miscellaneous Notebooks, 1910-1933; 7 Volumes (Box 14)
    This box contains 7 notebooks. 1 Account book from 1910, 1 catalog of bell collection, 1 notebook titled 'Art Motis', 1 notebook from 1916, 1 notebook labeled 'English Drama', 1 black album labeled 'Photos', and 1 brown album labeled 'Photos'. The brown album has photos of family, friends, and Dash (referenced in Control Folder).
- Artifacts
  - Stamp, Ace, and Coin Collection